Guide to the Herndon Dowling Herpetological Collection MS 059
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Herndon Dowling Herpetological Collection
1925-2014
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Pinou, Theodora
Dowling, Herndon G. (Herndon Glenn)
Jenner, Janann V.
MS 059
191
500 Linear Feet 110 boxes
Book boxes taped and sealed - in good condition File boxes mostly in good condition Map cabinets and base very rusted. Black cabinets have some scratches
Herdon Dowling was a systematic herpetologist with a primary interest in evolution. During his career Dowling worked in many projects and positions in the field of herpetology, won over half a dozen awards for his work, and authored over 200 publications.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains books (some oversized), research files containing drawings, journals, manuscript research, conference proceedings, specimens in jars and the cabinets, maps and drawings. These materials document Dowlings scientific career from the 1940s through the 2000s.
Generally, Dowling's "files" were kept in 4-drawer black file cabinets. The top draweres of 11 of his file cabinets were dedicated to files arranged by species name. These are processed in the Species Files series. The remaining file drawers remain unprocessed. The largest constituent grouping in this latter group are Dowlings Alphabetical Files. These are arranged by the last name of the scentist and they contain mostly article reprints but also include correspondence. The materials are boxed to precisely the demarcations of the file drawers. Where the contents of a file drawer exceed the capacity of a standard record center box, a smaller box is used to hold the overflow and is identifiable by a .l after the the box number. Unprocessed boxes are given a temporary box number assignment of ms059_files_##.
Dowling's Library is also part of this Collection and an inventory to those titles is maintained separate from this finding aid.
Other miscellaneous materials that are part of Dowling's collection but boxed will be processed as resources allow.
Biographical / Historical
Herdon Dowling (1921 – 2017) was born in Cullman, Alabama, to Herndon and Ada Dowling. His father was the superintendent of public schools in Tuscaloosa, and his mother worked for the Alabama Institute for the Deaf and Blind. Dowling grew up in Tuscaloosa, the oldest of the 3 Dowling children, and attended public school there until graduating from High School in 1938.
After high school Dowling attended the University of Alabama and graduated with a degree in biology in 1942. The same year he joined the U.S. Marine Corps as a commissioned officer and graduated officer training school in 1943.
In 1945 Dowling was stationed at Guadalcanal where his duties included interpreting aerial photographs of Okinawa Island, evaluating bomb sites, and eventually the collection of snake venom for the Navy. Dowling received a citation for excellent service for his work interpreting aerial photographs and was sent to Tianjin to assist with the Japanese surrender in that region in 1945. Dowling requested an honorable discharge in 1946, to continue his education, though he remained in the Marine Corps Reserves until 1959.
Upon being discharged from the active duty Dowling pursued his M.S. degree in Zoology at the University of Florida in Gainesville. His work there focused on the systematics of the Black Swamp Snake (Seminatrix pygea).
Dowling continued his studies at a Ph. D. program at the University of Michigan in the discipline of zoo-geography, with a focus on the systematics of the snake genus Elaphe in North America. Dowling completed his doctorate in 1951. He then went to teach at Haverford College, in Pennsylvania, for a year, followed by the University of Virginia's Mountain Lake Biological Station, and eventually the University of Arkansas. Dowling taught general biology, general zoology, as well as other related courses, and he introduced vertebrate natural history as a field course into the curriculum. Dowling left the University of Arkansas in 1959 because his contract was not renewed due to his refusal to comply with a newly enacted segregation policy at the university.
Dowling's next position was as Reptile Curator at the Bronx Zoo, a position he held from 1960-1967. During his time with the Bronx Zoo, Dowling traveled and researched extensively, conducting field work in such places as the Galapagos, Trinidad, and Martinique.
Concurrently, Dowling also held positions at the American Museum of Natural History (AMNH) in a grant funded capacity related to the generation of peer reviewed herpetological publications (1965-1973), as an adjunct professor at New York University (NYU) (1965-1973), and the University of Rhode Island (1964-1976). NYU eventually hired Dowling as an associate professor in 1973, and as a full professor in 1975. Dowling taught at NYU until his retirement in 1991. Dowling also eventually started his own journal, in 1973, called "Herpetological Information Search Systems" (HISS). During his career Dowling worked in many additional projects and positions in the field of herpetology, won over half a dozen awards for his work, and authored over 200 publications.
Citation: Stewart, Margaret M., and Joseph C. Micthell. "Historical Perspectives." Copeia 2013, no. 1 (March 2013): 166-72. Accessed March 23, 2017. http://www.asihcopeiaonline.org/doi/abs/10.1643/OT-12-142.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to portions of the collection is restricted. Much of this collection is only partially processed.
Provenance
Gift of the Dowling family and Jannan Jenner (wife of Herndon Dowling) through Dr. Theodora Pinou at WCSU.
Herpetology; Zoology--Pictorial works.; Snakes--Pictorial works.; Dowling, Herndon G. (Herndon Glenn), 1921-; journals (periodicals); Notes; Correspondence; Drawings.; Pinou, Theodora; Jenner, Janann V.
- Species Files
  - Ahaetulla, 1970 (Box 01, Folder 0001)
    General
    Folder notes: RS Se Co 807AHA06
    34023001500828
  - Genera of Colubrid Snakes, undated (Box 01, Folder 0002)
    Folder notes: On Table-DOWHG 967jly
    34023001500836
  - Colubridae Boiginae, 1950 (Box 01, Folder 0003)
    34023001500844
  - HP Colubridae, undated (Box 01, Folder 0004)
    Folder notes: ICA SCO FCO
    34023001500851
  - Colubridae, undated (Box 01, Folder 0005)
    34023001500869
  - Argyogena, undated (Box 01, Folder 0006)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO
    34023001500877
  - Colubridae Colubrinae, undated (Box 01, Folder 0007)
    34023001500885
  - Aeluroglena, undated (Box 01, Folder 0008)
    34023001500893
  - Arizona, undated (Box 01, Folder 0009)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 859ARI04
    34023001500901
  - Bogertophis, 1986 (Box 01, Folder 0010)
    Folder notes: 1 of 3, Other markings:
    34023001500919
  - Bogertophis, 1986 (Box 01, Folder 0011)
    Folder notes: 2 of 3, Other markings:
    34023001500927
  - Bogertophis, 1986 (Box 01, Folder 0012)
    Folder notes: 3 of 3, Other markings:
    34023001500810
  - Bogertophis Original, 1986 (Box 01, Folder 0013)
    34023001500935
  - Bogertophis Notes, 1986 (Box 01, Folder 0014)
    Folder notes: Hermage to Santa Rosalia
    34023001500943
  - Boiga, 1970 (Box 01, Folder 0015)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 826BOI02 BOIGA
    34023001500968
  - Cemophora, 1972 (Box 01, Folder 0016)
    Folder notes: RSSE CO 860CEM06 CEMOPHORA
    34023001500976
  - Cemophora coccinea, 1945-1970 (Box 01, Folder 0017)
    Folder notes: 1 of 5, Other markings:
    34023001500984
  - Cempohora- Copy, 1945-1970 (Box 01, Folder 0018)
    Folder notes: 2 of 5, Other markings:
    34023001500992
  - Cemophora- Specimen Invoices, 1945-1970 (Box 01, Folder 0019)
    Folder notes: 3 of 5, Other markings:
    34023001501008
  - Cemophora-Data Sheets, 1945-1970 (Box 01, Folder 0020)
    Folder notes: 4 of 5, Other markings:
    34023001501016
  - Cemophora-Letters, 1945-1970 (Box 01, Folder 0021)
    Folder notes: 5 of 5, Other markings:
    34023001501024
  - Chilomeniscus, 1972 (Box 01, Folder 0022)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 860CHI10
    34023001501032
  - Chionactis, undated (Box 01, Folder 0023)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 860CHI07
    34023001501040
  - Chrysopelea, 1970 (Box 01, Folder 0024)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 860CHR08
    34023001501057
  - Coelognathus, undated (Box 01, Folder 0025)
    Folder notes: 1 of 2, Other markings:
    34023001501065
  - Coelognathus, undated (Box 01, Folder 0026)
    Folder notes: 2 of 2, Other markings:
    34023001501073
  - Coluber, undated (Box 01, Folder 0027)
    34023001501081
  - Coluber Ref, 1981 (Box 01, Folder 0028)
    34023001501099
  - Coluber Ref, 1981 (Box 01, Folder 0029)
    34023001501107
  - Conopsis, 1997-2002 (Box 01, Folder 0030)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 858CON05
    34023001501115
  - Coronella, 2003 (Box 01, Folder 0031)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 768COR06
    34023001501123
- Species Files (with non-digitized drawings)
  - Crotaphopeltis, 1951-2002 (Box 01, Folder 0032)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 843CRO11
    34023001501263
  - Cyclophiops, 1969 (Box 02, Folder 0033)
    Folder notes: Ex Entechinus Ophoedrys, exc.
    34023001502113
  - Dasypeltis, 1970 (Box 02, Folder 0034)
    Folder notes: 1 of 2, Other markings: RS SE CO 830DAS07; notes, letters, ms; need: BOIE, 1826, COPF, 1886
    34023001502121
  - Dasypeltis, 1970 (Box 02, Folder 0035)
    Folder notes: 2 of 2, Other markings: RS SE CO 830DAS07; notes, letters, ms; need: BOIE, 1826, COPF, 1886
    34023001502139
  - Dasypeltis (literature), 1957-1960 (Box 02, Folder 0036)
    34023001502196
  - Dendrelaphis, 1971 (Box 02, Folder 0037)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 890DEN09
    34023001502188
  - Dendrophidion, 1970-1972 (Box 02, Folder 0038)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 843DEN10
    34023001502170
  - Dinodon, 1969-1970 (Box 02, Folder 0039)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853DIN04
    34023001502162
  - Dipsadoboa, 1951-1994 (Box 02, Folder 0040)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 858DIP07
    34023001502147
  - Dispholidus, 1970 (Box 02, Folder 0041)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 832DIS08
    34023001502154
  - Dromophis, undated (Box 02, Folder 0042)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO
    34023001502204
  - Dryadophis, 1963 (Box 02, Folder 0043)
    Folder notes: CAE COL COL [E Mastigodryas]
    34023001502212
  - Drymarchon, 1968-1969 (Box 02, Folder 0044)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 843DRY07
    34023001502220
  - Drymobius, 1968-1970 (Box 02, Folder 0045)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 843DRY06
    34023001502238
  - Drymoluber, 1970-1971 (Box 02, Folder 0046)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 930DRY07
    34023001502246
  - Dryophiops, undated (Box 02, Folder 0047)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 896DRY07
    34023001502261
  - Eirenis, 1971 (Box 02, Folder 0048)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 863EIR04
    34023001502469
  - Elachistodon, 1958-1970 (Box 02, Folder 0049)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 863ELA09
    34023001502477
  - Elaphe, 1965 (Box 02, Folder 0050)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 833ELA03
    34023001502485
  - Elaphe, 1941-1984 (Box 02, Folder 0051)
    34023001502493
  - Elaphe - MS Status of Scotophis Confinis, undated (Box 02, Folder 0052)
    34023001502501
  - Elaphe - Mertens and Dowling III, 1952 (Box 02, Folder 0053)
    34023001502519
  - Elaphe Carinata feeding modifications, 1958-1959 (Box 02, Folder 0054)
    34023001502527
  - Elaphe Flaviruga Cope II, 1952 (Box 02, Folder 0055)
    34023001502253
  - Elaphe - checklist IV, 1952-1954 (Box 02, Folder 0056)
    34023001502279
  - Elaphe - the Genus, 1965-1975 (Box 02, Folder 0057)
    34023001502295
  - Elaphe - MS re Schulz, 1997 (Box 02, Folder 0058)
    34023001502287
  - Elaphe - key, undated (Box 02, Folder 0059)
    34023001502303
  - Elaphe - General, 1977-1986 (Box 02, Folder 0060)
    34023001502311
  - Elaphe, 1951-1985 (Box 02, Folder 0061)
    34023001502329
  - Elaphe - checklist, 1952 (Box 02, Folder 0062)
    34023001502337
  - Elaphe - NEA E. Flavirufa, 1980-1993 (Box 02, Folder 0063)
    34023001502345
  - Elaphe - NEA E. Vulpina, 1940-1995 (Box 02, Folder 0064)
    Folder notes: contains photograph, Other markings:
    34023001502352
  - Elaphe: Oriental Regial, undated (Box 02, Folder 0065)
    34023001502386
  - Elaphe: Palaearctic region, 1952-2002 (Box 02, Folder 0066)
    Folder notes: contains photographs, Other markings:
    34023001502378
  - Entechinus = Cyclophiopes, undated (Box 02, Folder 0067)
    Folder notes: See Cundall, 1964 (Opheodrys), Other markings:
    34023001502360
  - Eremiophis, undated (Box 02, Folder 0068)
    34023001502451
  - Ficimia, 1971 (Box 02, Folder 0069)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 849FIC04
    34023001502436
  - Geagras, 1971-1987 (Box 02, Folder 0070)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 876GEA04
    34023001502428
  - (Gonaylosoma) Gonyosoma, 1968 (Box 02, Folder 0071)
    Folder notes: empty folder, Other markings: CAE COL COL
    x
  - Gonyophis, undated (Box 02, Folder 0072)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 891GON06
    34023001502550
  - Gonyosoma, 1970-1981 (Box 02, Folder 0073)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 828GON06
    34023001502634
  - Gonyosoma IV, 1956-1957 (Box 02, Folder 0074)
    Folder notes: A.C. Smith, Other markings:
    34023001502626
  - Gyalopion, 1975-1976 (Box 02, Folder 0075)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 860GYA06
    34023001502618
  - Haemorrhois, 1982-1983 (Box 02, Folder 0076)
    34023001502600
  - Heirophis, undated (Box 02, Folder 0077)
    Folder notes: empty folder, Other markings:
  - Iguanonathus, undated (Box 02, Folder 0078)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 8981GU10
    34023001502592
  - Lampropeltis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0079)
    34023001502584
  - Lampropeltis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0080)
    34023001502576
  - Lampropeltis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0081)
    34023001502568
  - Lampropeltis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0082)
    34023001502543
  - Lampropeltinine, undated (Box 03, Folder 0083)
    34023001502535
  - Leptodrymus, 1988 (Box 03, Folder 0084)
    34023001502410
  - Leptothis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0085)
    34023001502402
  - Liochlorophis (ex Opheodrys), 1941-1991 (Box 03, Folder 0086)
    Folder notes: CAE COL COL
    34023001502394
  - Liopeltis, 1972 (Box 03, Folder 0087)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 843LIO06
    34023001502642
  - Masticophis, 1942-1980 (Box 03, Folder 0088)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853MAS08
    34023001502667
  - Mastigodryas, 1941-2003 (Box 03, Folder 0089)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 955MAS09
    34023001502659
  - Meizodon, 1969-1980 (Box 03, Folder 0090)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 856MEI05
  - Opheodrys, 1965-1994 (Box 03, Folder 0091)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 843OPH06
    34023001502683
  - Opisthotropis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0092)
    Folder notes: CAE COL NAT, Other markings: RS SE CO 872OPI10
    34023001502691
  - Oxybelis, 1974-1991 (Box 03, Folder 0093)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 830OXY05
    34023001502709
  - Philothamnus, 1985 (Box 03, Folder 0094)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 840PHI09
    34023001502717
  - Pituophis, 1968 (Box 03, Folder 0095)
    Folder notes: 1 of 2; Contains 13 drawings of scale patterns - unlabeled., Other markings: RS SE CO 842PIT06
    34023001502725
  - Pituophis, 1968 (Box 03, Folder 0096)
    Folder notes: 2 of 2; Contains 13 drawings of scale patterns - unlabeled., Other markings: RS SE CO 842PIT06
    34023001502733
  - Prosymna, 1971 (Box 03, Folder 0097)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 849PRO05
    34023001502741
  - Pseudoficimia, 1971 (Box 03, Folder 0098)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 883PSE10
    34023001502758
  - Pseustes, undated (Box 03, Folder 0099)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 843PSE05
    34023001502766
  - Prosonora (see also Sonora), 2006 (Box 03, Folder 0100)
    Folder notes: RS SE COL
    34023001502774
  - Ptyas, 1969 (Box 03, Folder 0101)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 843PTY02
    34023001502782
  - Ptyas vs. Coluber, 1999 (Box 03, Folder 0102)
    34023001502790
  - Rhinocheilus, 1968 (Box 03, Folder 0103)
    Folder notes: RE SE CO 853RHI09
    34023001502808
  - Scaphiodontophis, 1973 (Box 03, Folder 0104)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 943SCA13
    34023001502915
  - Scaphiophis, 1971 (Box 03, Folder 0105)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 870SCA08
    34023001502923
  - Scoleophis, 2002 (Box 03, Folder 0106)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 843SCO08
    34023001502931
  - Senticolis (Temp?), 1960-1993 (Box 03, Folder 0107)
    34023001502949
  - Sibynophis, undated (Box 03, Folder 0108)
    Folder notes: CAE COL SIB?, Other markings: RS SE CO 843SIB07
    34023001503491
  - Sibynophis Ref, 1943-1970 (Box 04, Folder 0109)
    34023001503483
  - Simophis, 1972 (Box 04, Folder 0110)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 860SIM05
    34023001503475
  - Sonora, 1937-1979 (Box 04, Folder 0111)
    Folder notes: Includes negatives, Other markings: RS SE CO 853SON03
    34023001503467
  - Sonora in Arkansas, 1958-1959 (Box 04, Folder 0112)
    34023001503459
  - Spalerosophis, 1956-1971 (Box 04, Folder 0113)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 865SPH11
    34023001503442
  - Spilotes, 1969-1971 (Box 04, Folder 0114)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 830SPI05
    34023001503434
  - Stenorrhina, undated (Box 04, Folder 0115)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853STE08
    34023001503426
  - Stilosoma, 19701990 (Box 04, Folder 0116)
    Folder notes: 1 of 2, Other markings: RS SE CO 890STI06
    34023001503293
  - Stilosoma, 19701990 (Box 04, Folder 0117)
    34023001503285
  - Symphimus, 1971 (Box 04, Folder 0118)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 869SYM06
    34023001503277
  - Sympholis, 1971 (Box 04, Folder 0119)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 861SYM06
    34023001503269
  - Tantilla, 19701980 (Box 04, Folder 0120)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853TAN05
    34023001503251
  - Tantilla, 19701980 (Box 04, Folder 0121)
    34023001503244
  - Tantillita, 1986 (Box 04, Folder 0122)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 941TAN07
    34023001503236
  - Telescopus, 1971 (Box 04, Folder 0123)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 830TEL07
    34023001503376
  - Thelatornis, 19711979 (Box 04, Folder 0124)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 849THE08
    34023001503384
  - Thrasops, 1971 (Box 04, Folder 0125)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 857THR05
    34023001503392
  - Toluca, undated (Box 04, Folder 0126)
    Folder notes: SF Colubinae, T.SONORINE
    34023001503400
  - Trimetopon, 1949 (Box 04, Folder 0127)
    34023001503418
  - Trimorphodon, 19401969 (Box 04, Folder 0128)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 861TRI09
    34023001503301
  - Xenelaphis, undated (Box 04, Folder 0129)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 864XEN07
    34023001503319
  - Natricadae, 1979 (Box 04, Folder 0130)
    34023001503327
  - Natricadae, undated (Box 04, Folder 0131)
    34023001503335
  - Adelophis, 1968 (Box 04, Folder 0132)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO879ADE06
    34023001503343
  - Afronatrix, 1970 (Box 04, Folder 0133)
    Folder notes: B 3(2)!, Other markings: RS SE CO
    34023001503350
  - Amphiesma, 19621970 (Box 04, Folder 0134)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 854AMP06
    34023001503368
  - Amphiesmoides, 1961 (Box 04, Folder 0135)
    Folder notes: CAE COL NAT NAT, Other markings: RS SE CO 961AMP10
    34023001502956
  - Atretium, 1970 (Box 04, Folder 0136)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 861ATR05
    34023001502964
  - Balanophis, undated (Box 04, Folder 0137)
    34023001502972
  - Clonophis, 1968 (Box 04, Folder 0138)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 889CLO06
    34023001502980
  - Heliophis, undated (Box 04, Folder 0139)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 942HEL05
  - Hydraethiops, 1970 (Box 04, Folder 0140)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 872HYD09
    34023001503004
  - Limnophis, 1971 (Box 04, Folder 0141)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 865LIM06
    34023001503012
  - Lycognathopis, 1988 (Box 04, Folder 0142)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 893LYC11
    34023001503020
  - [No title], Scopenophis, 1980 (Box 04, Folder 0143)
    Folder notes: RS SE NA
    34023001503038
  - Natriciteres, 19711972 (Box 04, Folder 0144)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 953NAT09
    34023001503046
  - Natrix, 19681971 (Box 04, Folder 0145)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 768NAT03
    34023001503053
  - Nerodia, 19341992 (Box 04, Folder 0146)
    Folder notes: Notes on front of folder., Other markings: RS SE CO
    34023001503061
  - Parahelicops = opisthotrophis, undated (Box 05, Folder 146.a)
    Folder notes: Empty folder, Other markings:
  - Pararhabdophis, undated (Box 05, Folder 146.b)
    Folder notes: 1 computer card, 1 index card, Other markings: RS SE CO 934PAR11
  - Pseusdagkistrodon, undated (Box 05, Folder 146.c)
  - Regina, 19601971 (Box 05, Folder 0147)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853REG03
    34023001503079
  - Rhabdophis, 19701990 (Box 05, Folder 0148)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 843RHA07
    34023001503087
  - Scopelophis, 1990 (Box 05, Folder 0149)
    Folder notes: NT? (Xenod.?)
    34023001503202
  - Seminatrix, 19501990 (Box 05, Folder 0150)
    Folder notes: Temp
    34023001503228
  - Seminatrix Account, 1997 (Box 05, Folder 0151)
    34023001503210
  - Seminatrix Pygaea -- Work Sheet, 19461948 (Box 05, Folder 0152)
    34023001503194
  - Sinonatrix, undated (Box 05, Folder 0153)
    Folder notes: B, Other markings: RS SE CO
    34023001503178
  - Storeria, 1972 (Box 05, Folder 0154)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853STO05
    34023001503186
  - Thamnophis Proposal, 19511996 (Box 05, Folder 0155)
    34023001503152
  - Thamnophis, 19451990 (Box 05, Folder 0156)
    Folder notes: 1 of 3, Other markings: RS SE CO 843THA07
    34023001503160
  - Thamnophis, 19451990 (Box 05, Folder 0157)
    Folder notes: 2 of 3, Other markings: RS SE CO 843THA07
    34023001503145
  - Thamnophis, 19451990 (Box 05, Folder 0158)
    Folder notes: 3 of 3, Other markings: RS SE CO 843THA07
    34023001503137
  - Thamnophis, 19301970 (Box 05, Folder 158a)
    Folder notes: Unfoldered books
    34023001503517
  - Tropidoclonion, 1972 (Box 05, Folder 0159)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 860TRO11
    34023001503129
  - Tropidonophis, 19711988 (Box 05, Folder 0160)
    34023001503111
  - Virginia, 1972 (Box 05, Folder 0161)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853VIR05
    34023001503095
  - Xenochrophis, 19651985 (Box 05, Folder 0162)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 864XEN09
    34023001503103
  - Cae Lam Cal Pareatinae, undated (Box 05, Folder 0163)
    34023001503616
  - Aplopeltura (Cae Lam Ca Pareatinae), 1970 (Box 05, Folder 0164)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 853APL08
    34023001503608
  - Pareas, 19691971 (Box 05, Folder 0165)
    Folder notes: Cae Lam Cal Par, Other markings: RS SE CO 830PAR03
    34023001503624
  - Xenoderminae, 19641970 (Box 05, Folder 0166)
    Folder notes: SE CAE ACR XEN
    34023001503590
  - Macropisthodon, undated (Box 05, Folder 0167)
    Folder notes: RS SE CO 893MAC11
    34023001503582
  - Anoplohydrus, undated (Box 05, Folder 0168)
    Folder notes: Cae Homaropsiae, probable Xenoderm, Other markings: RS SE CO 909ANO09
    34023001503525
  - Achalinus, undated (Box 05, Folder 0169)
    Folder notes: Cae Acr Xen - OC PC, Other markings: RS SE CO 869ACH06
    34023001503541
  - Aspidura, 1971 (Box 05, Folder 0170)
    Folder notes: Ceylon, Cae, Acr, Xen, Other markings: RS SE 830ASP05
    34023001503533
  - Blythia, undated (Box 05, Folder 0171)
    Folder notes: India-Burma, Other markings: RS SE CAE ACR XEN
    34023001503574
  - Bothrolycus, 1970 (Box 05, Folder 0172)
    Folder notes: Cae Lam Acr Xen?, Other markings: 874BOT08
    34023001503566
  - Bothrophthalmus, 1970 (Box 05, Folder 0173)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM ACR XEN?, Other markings: 863BOT12
    34023001503558
  - Brachyorrhas, 1970 (Box 05, Folder 0174)
    Folder notes: ACR XEN AI, Other markings: RS SE CO
    34023001503640
  - Calamariinae, undated (Box 05, Folder 0175)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM CAL, Other markings:
    34023001503632
  - Calamaria, undated (Box 05, Folder 0176)
    Folder notes: CAE LAM CAL CAL, Other markings: RS SE CO 827CAL06
    34023001503764
  - Calamorhabdium, undated (Box 05, Folder 0177)